BRYAN BARRIENTOS

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Memphis, Tennessee | (479) 462-5865 | bryan.barrientos83@gmail.com | LinkedIn | b-barrientos · GitHub

SUMMARY

A constructive and determined Software Engineer with over four years of demonstrated success in API development, database management, clean architecture, testing paradigms, front-end UI, application development, complex technical troubleshooting, and process improvement. Adaptable in driving successful projects, supporting and servicing clients, and collaborating with cross-functional departments. Proven aptitude for implementing strategies and solutions to drive efficiency, ensure quality, and achieve exceptional results.

Adaptable | Decisive | Thoughtful | Self-Motivated | Open-Minded | Quick Study | Efficient

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: Kotlin, Java, Python, SQL, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, PL/SQL, XML
- Frameworks and Libraries: Jetpack Compose, Dagger/Hilt, TensorFlow, TF Lite, ML Kit, Room Database, Gradle, Pluto, Timber, Koin, Coroutines, Dependency Injection, REST API, MVC, MVVM (Model View ViewModel)
- Tools: Git, Atlassian Products (Jira, Confluence, BitBucket), Firebase Console / Services, Android Studio, VS Code, Figma, CircleCI, CI/CD
- Spoken Languages: Fluent/Native English, Fluent/Native Spanish

EXPERIENCE

FIRST ORION, Little Rock, Arkansas

Associate Android Software Engineer, 2022-2024

- Developed applications, using MVVM and clean architecture principles. Created UI components and screens, using Jetpack Compose and traditional XML.
- Initial research and setup done for automated regression tests for Engage and T-Mobile Scam Shield applications
- Wrote unit tests and automated UI tests, which increased code coverage for applications from 60% to over 80%
- Created Build Pipelines, using CircleCI and wrote configuration to add features and aid on releases for applications.
- Reorganized internal team presentation process to better outline what assisted the team in productivity, engagement, and interest, helping bridge gap between remote and in office team members.
- Created in-house internal development tool app to help assist android developers across the company with debugging.

ACXIOM, Conway, Arkansas

Associate Solution Developer, 2021-2022

- Helped develop SQL Scripts, create/maintain database objects, and develop batch processes using complex SQL queries.
- Led several database processes for monthly releases.
- Performed on-call rotations to resolve issues with reporting/scheduled jobs running on Acxiom internal tools.
- Resolved any issues encountered with batch process and SQL scripts.
- Generated reports using PL/SQL by exporting data into excel, csv and XML files and importing data into SQL tables.

ACXIOM, Conway, Arkansas

Intern Tester, 2020-2021; Intern Solution Developer, 2021

- Resolved support tasks and tickets escalated to the support team via clients.
- Led monthly releases involving proprietary versioning tools, server work, and postman.
- Researched on databases, servers, and proprietary data visualization tools such as Kibana and AppDynamics.
- Ensured all PII and other data was handled properly and according to guidelines.
- Tracked test cases via Jira and TestRail for deployment.
- Performed QA best practices such as regression testing, smoke testing, and integration testing.

EDUCATION